Maxime Liron's Resume

5 Full Stack Web developer

Bilingual -- English and French, canadian and french citizenships

Email maximeliron@gmail.com

Skype maxime.liron

Github github.com/ximus

Profile

Web developer from the south of France, have worked in San Francisco for the past 2+ years. I have a strong interest in all fields of technology, and am very keen on always learning & applying new skills. Over the past 4 years, I have worked hard to gain as much concrete experience in the field of web development and web interaction design as possible, including good understanding of web systems.

I work mainly on the technical side of web applications, but I am always attentive to the bigger picture. I am most productive when I understand the mission behind a project.

Skills Summary

Front-end

 HTML 0000000 • CSS, SASS 000000 000000 Mobile 000000 Javascript 0000000 JQuery AngularJS 0000000 0000000 EmberJS Ability to Learn 0000000

Culture

Communication Collaboration

Core Mission Understanding

Active listening Independent

Attention to Detail Dedication

Hard Working Easy-going

Back-end

Ruby 0000000 Rails 0000000 MySQL 00000 000000 Redis 000000 Git System Architectures 000000 • Sys Admin (Unix-like) 0000000 0000000 Go (language) 0000000 Ability to Learn

Misc Technical

Hadoop Java CoffeeScript

SproutCore SpineJS Ansible C

PHP

Experience

Six years of independent work, followed by two years of employment in Silicon Valley.

Web Engineering

- Substantial front-end experience
- · Designed multiple web applications from the ground up
- Core participation in large web deployment, ~6 million users
- · Held significant responsibilities in both front-end and back-ends of web systems
- Handled critical production incidents effectively
- Able to understand complex scenarios quickly:
 - Performance monitoring
 - · Systems visibility, metrics
 - Payment systems
 - · Large email delivery infrastructure
- Test driven development and experience with a QA team
- Utilized tools for investigating production systems (strace, dtrace, tcpdump, ...)
- · Systems design
 - Understand the system as whole, thinking further than the business application code
 - Network architecture, REST principles
 - Studied and deployed Cloud architectures

Product Development

- Participated in the thought process behind the marketing of multiple products
- · Participated in the successful promotion of a new service within a new and disruptive industry trend
- Allowed a sales team to greatly augment their efficiency (and happiness) by architecting a collaborative web app
- Core participation in data-driven product development
- Product developement through experimentation
- · Development and implementation of data models for product behavior

Work Environments

- Worked in distributed teams (US east/west, India, France)
- · Lean, fast moving startup environments
- Github-style, flat organisation
- Experience with a corporate envirnoment and its constraints (need for stability, planning)
- Led a session on scaling cloud infrastuctures at Code Camp (http://www.siliconvalley-codecamp.com/)

Past Projects

Senior Software Engineer Rearden Commerce, Homerun.com (http://www.deem.com/)

03/2012 - 09/2013

contact with: VP of Analytics, Offers engineering team, Offers product team

tools used: Ruby, Hadoop, Postfix, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Coffeescript, SASS

Core participation in a lean e-commerce engineering team (payments, analytics, email, both front-end and back-end). Learned to use data and analytics to drive decision making. Regularly participated in product development. Partner relationships with industry heavyweights.

Mobile Web App Design | Blurt (http://www.blurt.net/)

2011

contact with: Founder

tools used: HTML/CSS, Javascript, Coffeescript, SASS

Created a consumer oriented mobile app for mobile commerce. Used the latest techniques in CSS3 animation and touch functionality. Learned how to deal with the constraints of mobile devices.

Web Design | Love the World (http://www.lovetheworld.com/)

05/2011 - 06/2011

contact with: Head of communications

tools used: HTML/CSS, Javascript, RaphaelJS (SVG framework)

Implemented a CO₂ module to enable visitors to measure their country's CO ₂ footprint

Web Application Design | MD Architecture

05/2010 - 07/2010

contact with: CEO

tools used: HTML/CSS, Ruby on Rails

Designed and implemented a muti-user online file sharing platform for the construction of a large High School. The platform includes complex authorization and roles model, and basic email sharing capabilities.

Web Application Design | Modenature (construction) (http://www.modenature.pro/)

07/2009 - 11/2009

contact with: CEO

tools used: Adobe Air, Flex (Actionscript framework), Ruby

A major learning experience. Built a collaborative web application to enable the sales team to work (much) more efficiently. Reception by users was great.

Visual Design | Qualinetwork (http://www.qualinetwork.com/)

05/2011 - 06/2011

contact with: Founder and CEO tools used: HTML/CSS, Actionscript

Designed and implemented a visual graph to visualize customer feedback for products sold through e-commerce

Web Design | Scalr (http://wwww.scalr.net/)

2009

contact with: Founder and CEO

tools used: HTML/CSS, Illustrator, Photoshop, Mindtouch (wiki platform), Camtasia Studio (screencast recording)

Participated in the branding thought process, recorded screencasts, designed the web site. Gave me a strong understanding of cloud computing

Web Marketing | Bazile Telecom (http://www.bazile.fr/)

2008

contact with: CEO, Marketing Manager

tools used: HTML/CSS, Actionscript, Illustrator, Photoshop

Designed and implemented an small interactive client-side app so people could better understand the client's product.

09/2007 - 01/2008 Intern | NuGraphic

contact with: CEO

tools used: HTML/CSS, Javascript, PHP, Illustrator, Photoshop

My stepping stone into the web. Learned the basics of the web from some of the best (now working for Zynga). Participated in web design, branding, web strategy and e-commerce works.

Other Sites I've built:

forgedemontolieu.com (http://forgedemontolieu.com/)

Bed & Breakfast in the south of France

lalettrevolee.fr

Local bookshop

(http://lalettrevolee.fr/)

francoisecullet.com

,

Artist in the south of France, earlier work

(http://francoisecullet.com/)
oliviadegasquet.com

Another Artist, earlier work

(http://oliviadegasquet.com/)

Education

High School -- I was in boarding school in Canada (Shawnigan Lake School (http://www.shawnigan.ca/)) then in an international High school in the south of France, Lycée George Duby (http://www.lyc-luynes.ac-aix-marseille.fr/).

Self taught -- My interest in the technical web started at 17 years old. Learned extensively through books, open source projects and online material, clocked in *many* hours watching footage of conference talks. Learned loads through client projects.

I left university after two years of physics and chemistry to pursue my web endeavors. The skills I learned did not require me to go to university but I do not rule out going back to university for more advanced skills.

I have a decent understanding of core computer science concepts (algorithms, compilers, ...). I am conscious of their roles and implications, though coming from a self-taught background, I have not studied them thoroughly. I am confident on my ability to strengthen my understanding of algorithms if the job requires it. I am willing to do whatever is necessary to meet requirements.

Interests

These pique my interest

Economics and finance World dynamics Enabling people to do more using the web

Innovative and creative thinking People Understanding things, learning

Designing web system architectures I appreciate well-designed user interfaces Technology Robotics

Data Visualization Travel -- Discovered North America, South America, South Asia, Europe with a back pack

Sports -- Main sport is tennis, used to be rugby, I hike and run regularly Outdoors Climbing Art

Music Wine